osa.org 2018-03-15

# Privacy Policy | The Optical Society

## OSA Privacy Policy

**Information Collection**  
OSA and the OSA Foundation (collectively "OSA") are the sole owners of the information collected on www.osa.org and affiliated sites. OSA collects information at several different points on the web site.

Periodically, a user may be required to complete a form to register for OSA events or to contribute to the OSA Foundation. The form requires a user to provide his/her contact information. This information is used to contact the user about the event for which the user has registered or related events, services and products. The attendee lists for OSA Topical Meetings are made available to attendees for networking purposes.  
Additionally, authors and reviewers may provide personal information in the process of submitting a manuscript or review, or when establishing reviewer expertise profiles. OSA does not distribute personally identifiable information except as is consistent with the scholarly publishing peer-review process (e.g., for the purpose of introducing your submission to an editorial review board).  
While placing an order or making a contribution, a user is asked to provide contact information and financial information. This information is used for billing and receipting purposes and to fill a customer's order. If there is a problem processing an order or contribution, the information may be used to contact the user.

Information is also collected through cookies, log files, link tracking, and/or third party service providers. Some of the collected information is tied to the user's personally identifiable information to provide offers and improve the content of the site for the user.

**Cookies**  
To enhance the performance and functionality of our site, we use session, persistent and third-party “cookies” that store a small piece of data on a users’ computers and collect certain information about the users’ visit to our site. We also use cookies to understand users’ browsing and buying activities so that we can measure the success of online advertising campaigns we run on the site. Our site also uses web beacons (either directly or from our partners), along with cookies, to determine if a user has visited a particular website. These beacons help us to provide more relevant advertising to the user, as well measuring the success of an advertising campaign. They provide no personally identifiable information. 

Cookies are small text files that web servers typically send to a user’s computer when they visit a website. Cookies are stored as text files on the user’s hard drive, and can be accessed by web servers when the user visits a website or views an advertisement. A session cookie is a cookie that stores information as a user is using the site but is deleted once the browser session is finished. A persistent cookie is a cookie that stores information as a user uses the site and stores and uses that information in connection with future visits of the user to the site. Third-party cookies and/or web beacons are cookies or web beacons provided by our technology and/or advertising partners. Any third-party cookie or web beacon that we authorize for use on the site only collects that information described below for the same stated purposes as if we were directly collecting the information. For a third-party cookie or web beacon, the third-party will have access to the collected information in order to provide us with information or services to enhance the performance and functionality of the site. We have not authorized the third-party to use the information for any other purpose.  
The cookies and web beacons we use collect non-personally identifiable information about users of the site, including: IP address , browser used to access the site, date and time, the URL of the page being loaded, users who have visited a particular website(s), any previously assigned cookie identification (a unique identifier assigned to a user to identify repeat visitors), browser window size, the geographic location of the user, and the device and operating system used to access the site. The information we collect from these cookies and web beacons is used to determine information about a user’s visit to our site, including the number of visits, average time spent, pages viewed, navigation history through the website, and other statistics. This information is used to enhance the user’s experience while visiting our site and to improve the performance of our site by, among other things, allowing us to monitor site performance, make the site easier to use, measure the effectiveness of promotional placements, and tailor the site (including the ads and offers a user receives) to better match a user’s interests and preferences. 

Users who prefer not to accept cookies can set their Internet browser to notify them when they receive a cookie or to prevent cookies from being placed on their hard drive. If you consent to our collection of cookies and you subsequently wish to withdraw your consent, you will need to manage the settings on your web browser to delete all cookies and disallow further acceptance of cookies. Please note that disabling cookies on your browser will prevent us from tracking your activities in relations to our site; however, it may also disable some of the functions and features of the site and the site may not work properly.

By continuing to use our site, you are agreeing to our placing cookies and/or web beacons on your computer in order to analyze the way you use our site. Please read this cookie policy carefully for more details about the information we collect when you use the site.

If you do not wish to accept cookies or web beacons in connection with your use of this site, please discontinue use of the site.

Use of Google Universal Analytics  
OSA uses “Google Analytics”, including its “Universal Analytics,” to collect information about use of this site. Google Analytics collects information such as how often users visit this site, what pages they visit when they do so, and what other sites they used prior to coming to this site.  _OSA uses the information it gets from Google Analytics only to improve this site.  _Google Analytics collects only the IP address assigned to you on the date you visit this site, rather than your name or other identifying information. In accordance with the [Google Analytics Terms of Use](http://www.google.com/analytics/tos.html) (as [amended for government websites](http://www.howto.gov/sites/default/files/google-analytics-tos-amendment.pdf "amendments for government websites of the Google Analytics Terms of Use")), OSA does not combine the information collected through the use of Google Analytics with personally identifiable information. Although Google Analytics plants a permanent cookie on your web browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit this site, the cookie cannot be used by anyone but Google. Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to this site is restricted by the [Google Analytics Terms of Use](http://www.google.com/analytics/tos.html) (as [amended for government websites](http://www.howto.gov/sites/default/files/google-analytics-tos-amendment.pdf "amendments for government websites of the Google Analytics Terms of Use")) and the [Google Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/privacypolicy.html). You can prevent Google Analytics from recognizing you on return visits to this site by [disabling cookies](http://www.usa.gov/optout_instructions.shtml) on your browser.

Google Analytics uses cookies to define user sessions, which allows for the collection of data about how visitors are using the websites. Google Analytics uses only first-party cookies for data analysis. This means that the cookies are linked to a specific website domain, and Google Analytics will only use that cookie data for statistical analysis related to your browsing behavior on that specific website. According to Google, the data collected cannot be altered or retrieved by services from other domains.

If you choose, you can opt out by turning off cookies in the preferences settings in your web browser. For more information on Google Analytics or Universal Analytics, please visit [Google Analytics](http://www.google.com/analytics/).

**Database Confidentiality**  
Contact information for OSA members is automatically included in the directory of members, which is available to all members, unless an OSA member has opted out.

OSA does not sell or share email addresses with other organizations without the express permission of the user. OSA does not sell contact information from its database to non-corporate members.

**Log Files  **  
Web site log files are used to store information such as: internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks. This information is used to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movements within the site and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information. The log files are used by utility tracking software to analyze user movement.

Database download logs track which articles have been downloaded by which IP address (for institutional subscriptions) or individual (for individual subscriptions). If downloads exceed a standard level, the individual or institution will receive a warning and service may be disconnected. This action is taken to ensure that the systems remain available to all subscribers. Individuals have access to a report that details the articles they have downloaded. Institutions have access to a report that details the articles downloaded by IP addresses at their institution.

**Email tracking**  
Link tracking is used within HTML-based emails to track which links have been clicked by the recipients. This tracking provides a means to measure the effectiveness of marketing campaigns.

**Legal Disclaimer**  
Though every effort is made to preserve user privacy, it may be necessary to disclose personal information when required by law, such as in compliance with a court order or other legal or governmental process.

**Notifications**  
OSA may use a user's information to provide the user with information on new products, services, or upcoming events. More and more OSA information is provided by email, so users may not receive notices on these subjects if they opt-out. Users who wish not to receive email from OSA, may use the “unsubscribe” link provided at the bottom of every email.

OSA may also use user's contact information to reach the user through phone, mail or fax. Users who wish to be removed from all contact by these methods may contact OSA’s Customer Service department by visiting OSA’s Help Center, [submitting a Help Ticket](https://account.osa.org/eweb/DynamicPage.aspx?WebCode=MyAcctRequestHelp&action=add), by calling us at +1 202.416.1907 (Worldwide) or 1.800.766.4672 (US/Canada only) or by e-mailing us at [custserv@osa.org](mailto:custserv@osa.org).

OSA members may not opt out of OSA business mailings such as the election mailing.

**Links**  
This Web site may contain links to non-OSA web sites. OSA is not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites.  This privacy policy applies solely to information collected by OSA-hosted and maintained Web sites.  We encourage users to be aware of the privacy practices of any non-OSA web site before disclosing any personally identifiable information on that site.

**Online Discussion Forums**  
Whenever users voluntarily disclose personal information online, that information can be collected and used by others. By posting personal information online that is publicly accessible, users may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return.

**Security**  
This Web site takes every precaution to protect user information. When users submit sensitive information via the Web site, their information is protected both online and off-line.

SSL encryption software is used on forms requesting financial information. Full credit card numbers are not stored in our databases.

User information is restricted within the OSA offices. Employees who need the information to perform a specific job are granted access to personally identifiable information. Servers that store personally identifiable information are in a locked facility.

**Correcting/Updating/Deleting/Deactivating Personal Information**  
If a user's personally identifiable information changes, or if a user no longer desires the services provided, contact OSA’s Customer Service department by visiting OSA’s Help Center, [submitting a Help Ticket](https://account.osa.org/eweb/DynamicPage.aspx?WebCode=MyAcctRequestHelp&action=add), by calling us at +1 202.416.1907 (Worldwide) or 1.800.766.4672 (US/Canada only) or by e-mailing us at [custserv@osa.org](mailto:custserv@osa.org).

**Modifications to the Policy**  
OSA may modify, add or remove portions of the Privacy Policy at any time. Customer information may be used for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in the privacy notice. Information practice changes will be posted on this Web site.

**Contact Information**  
If users have any questions or suggestions regarding this privacy policy, please contact OSA at:

**OSA – The Optical Society of America**  
2010 Massachusetts Ave NW  
Washington, DC 20036  
202.223.8130 Ph  
202.223.1096 Fax  
email: [info@osa.org ](mailto:info@osa.org)
